Good morning. So I just wanted to let y'all know, if you didn't know, my show, What Would
the Ancestors Say? I'll be doing a reading on Saturday, September 6th at the People's
Forum. You can get your, you can reserve a seat by donating to the People's Forum or
you can come here or you can show up and get a seat for free. But it is on, damn it, it's
on 9-6, yeah. I'm still, I'm still in November. I mean, I'm still in August. NYC Free Show
9-6 Link in Bio. Thank you. Those are my paintings. I really wish I had more time to paint. Soon
come, soon come. Yes, it says 8-6, but I obviously mean 9-6. Yeah, I obviously mean 9-6.
So I just wanted to read a little bit of it to spark any of you guys' curiosities. And
also because when I read it, it helps me to know where I'm going because I need to finish
writing this particular section today. Okay? So this segment is about the contextualizing
of what it means to be Black in the United States. So that is what, so the show, What Would
the Ancestors Say? is a show in segments. Some are done as characters. Some are done as monologues.
Some are done as, you know, kind of like lectures. And so this one is more of a lecture.
Why would she need, why does she need to address MAGA influencers?
I don't understand why you all want articles about the obvious. The point of journalism is to reveal
that which is not being told, to expose truth. I don't understand. Why do you need articles about
truth that's already out here? Why is that valuable to you? I don't get it. Think about it.
You already know that. So why do you need that? What you didn't know was that Democrats are doing
the same thing. That is also problematic. How do you not know respectfully? It's blatantly obvious
respectfully. And how about you write that article? I have never understood the concept of,
but what about? I've never understood it. We're not talking about white leftists covering up their
racism. She didn't just talk about black influencers. Like, what are we, what are we talking about?
Don't tell me what to do, Sanford. I will talk about what the fuck I want to talk about. I hate
when y'all come on here and you think that you're supporting me when you tell me, don't worry about
them. I am a grown woman. I will address what I want to address. Like, so I just, I really want you
all to elevate your media literacy. I really want you to elevate your media literacy. You need to know
that those who you consider to be better are not. You need to know that. You need to know
that a party that you consider to be different is not. You need to know that.
You need to have the lie dispelled. It's imperative. Democrats and Republicans were never for black
people at ever point, at ever any point. They were never for black people ever go watch the movie
Lincoln. And you tell me if Democrats and Republicans were ever for black people ever. They have never
been for black people. Neither of them have ever been for black people. They have never been for
the people. Did you know that? This system was not created for public servants. It was created to give
white men the power to have dominance over other white men. It is a mimic of the monarchy. Yes.
And if you know anything about the monarchy, you know that there were lords. Okay. You know that
there were lords. You know that everyone wanted to be invited to court. You know that people had their
lands. And then they had peasants. And they had serfs. And any effort to do something different than
this has been undermined militarily. Not enough people know history. Not enough people know history.
And that's why I don't want to have any conversations with people. I had a really, really annoying
conversation the other day with somebody who felt that their minimal opinion, their, their opinion
based on minimal research was more important or was, was just as valuable as an academic and former
black Panther. I told them that an academic and intellectual and author, a revolutionary and
former black Panther had this thing to say. And they said, I disagree. And I said, well,
based on what grounds I just disagree. And she was saying about something that had happened in the
black Panthers and he was disagreeing that it happened. And I said, wait, what grounds on what
grounds do you have to disagree? Do you have research on this? Well, no. Have, have you, so you, okay.
So you haven't done research on this. You, were you a black Panther? No. I said, so I'm trying to
understand why you feel that your opinion on this is of any value, let alone of equal value to hers.
And he said, well, I'm just saying like, I've never, I've just never seen any example of what she's
saying. I said, but you haven't done any research. So where, what, what is, what is the, what is the,
the lack of presence of you seeing something have to do with its ability?
If you've, it'd be different if you had done extensive research. Oh, so I feel, so, so because
I'm not an expert, I can't speak on it. Correct. Correct. Yes. Because you're not an expert,
you should not speak on it. You should have curiosity. Yeah. But your opinion is invalid.
And the only thing that kept me at that table was that I actually liked them as people. But the next
time we get together, I'm going to make it clear from jump. Like the next time that a conversation
goes in this direction, I'm just going to leave because this is a complete waste of my time.
And it is actually insulting to my intelligence to engage in this type of conversation. So, um,
all right. Are y'all ready for me to read a bit of this play? It's not a lot. I'm so glad Issa said
you're 100% bipolar and need your meds. I never heard Issa say that, but even if she did say that
again, if you are not an expert, why are you talking? Who, who would Issa Rae be to diagnose me?
She is a writer. So that would have zero validity.
Um, all right. They never wanted us here. You understand that, right? Black people as a free
people were never wanted here. From the Jamestown colony to the United States, we have always been
treated like the roommate you hate, but that you need because without them, you can't make the mortgage.
You own the house, but you're incapable of maintaining it. So just seeing them pisses you
off. Cause it reminds you that no matter the lie, you tell yourself about how superior you are,
you are insufficient. This resentment has you doing wicked shit, being difficult and straight up lying.
Some may say, so then why doesn't the roommate AKA black folks just move out because they built the
damn house and ain't got paid for it. Made all the furniture too. That's the United States of
America. They never wanted us here as a free people. When Lincoln signed the Emancipation
Proclamation in 1863, it wasn't to free the slaves. It was a military strategy that provided soldiers for
the union army. He later met with black leaders to suggest sending free black folks anywhere,
Central America, Central America, Africa, Haiti, but they weren't having it. So he said, all right,
well, let's figure this. We are family thing out. Two years later on January 16th, 1865, in the thick
of the civil war, union general William Tecumseh Sherman proclaimed special field orders number 15,
which said, we're going to give 40 acres of land to some free folks. And they did.
But slavery still was not abolished in the constitution. The all white house of representatives
comprised of men concerned with, as the film Lincoln called the nigguration of America had no interest in
racial equality. By a narrow margin, Lincoln managed to get the 13th amendment to
pass through Congress solely on the grounds that Negroes were equal in the law,
but not in the flesh. The civil war ended on April 9th, 1865. And two weeks later,
Lincoln's presidency ended on April 15th, 1965, when they took him out while he was at the theater
watching the play. Pop, pop. By the end of the year, his replacement, Andrew Johnson,
snatched them 40 acres back with the quickness, welcomed the Confederate States back into Congress
and immediately placed black folks back into the path of slavery with the implementation of the black
codes. Laws that system, that systemically prevented newly freed black folks from participating in society,
in American society equally on any level. Because its principal effort was not to correct the wrongs done
to black folks, but instead to stitch back together a country formed in capitalist exploitation.
The post-Civil War reconstruction was actually deconstruction. It was destruction of any chance
at putting the United States on a path of redemption. They never wanted us here. Every day, black folks are
reminded that this place does not like us. Not only do we spend money with slave owners on it. Wait,
sorry. Not only do we spend money with slave owners on it, we spend money with a plantation on it.
Monticello, Thomas Jefferson's biggest plantation, he had others, enslaved 400 people. It was known to be brutal
and it is literally on the back of the nickel. And to be extra petty, they put the president that ended slavery
on a brown coin. Ain't that some shit? Ha! They never wanted us here. So we said, fine, we will go over there
and mine the business that pays us. We built our towns. They burnt them down. We raised villages.
They flooded them. We founded our communities. And they dismantled them with highways. We fought in their wars.
Then got lynched on U.S. soil. We made our music. Then they put their face on it and used it. Don't y'all see?
We are still living in a diminished destiny. This country has never righted its wrong because it has
never seen them that way. Sorry, hold on. This country has never righted its wrongs because it's
never seen them in that way. Instead of an apology and actual links and actual shifts in culture
and ideology, they give those they've harmed a pittance, a pat on the head, and the option to
participate in their capitalist scheme. We've all fallen for it. Native Americans and casinos,
Asian Americans and the model minority, Black Americans and industry, except cars. What is that?
Why is there Toyota and Mercedes and Hyundai? But we have yet to see a Keisha Turbo XL come off the
assembly line, right? With setting head rests, okay? And bamboo rims. Come on now. Folks have been so engaged
in political activism, they didn't realize that we need cultural activism. The laws may have changed,
but the actual heart of this country has never changed. That's why every time any law is passed
that seems like it could benefit Black people in any way, it's thrown at us like, oh, here nigga,
damn. Look at the Civil Rights Act of 1965. Black people never stopped organizing and fighting for
their rights. And by 1964, they had risen to a fever pitch. After 10 years of boycotts, lunch counter sit-ins,
the 16th Street Baptist Church bombing that killed four little girls, and countless other examples of
white Americans being agents of Ku Klux capacity, a change was about to come. On June 18th, 1964,
down in St. Augustine, Florida, a combo of Black and white protesters decided they weren't going to sit in,
they was going to jump in. And that's exactly what they did in the Monson Motor Hall, whites-only pool.
Now, you may remember the photo of the hotel's owner, shades-on blazer, billowing in the hot air of his
hatred while he poured acid in the pool. And the protesters screamed and scrambled to safety. That
picture was plastered all over the news. And after an 82-day filibuster, the longest in history,
the next day, the Civil Rights Act of 1964 was passed that outlawed discrimination based on race,
color, religion, sex, and national origin. If you would like to see more of this,
then you can be with us on Saturday, September 6th at the People's Forum, where I will be reading the
entire play for the people. And you can also watch it. And this is a free show. You can reserve your
seat by giving a donation to the People's Forum. And you can see the show virtually at a link provided
in the bio. So in my bio. So hopefully you all will be there and get to see the process of this
because it is something that I really believe in. And it is a continuance of my dedication to
edutain you all. Have a great Labor Day. If you have the day off, I hope that you
spend it in... It's a one-woman show. I hope that you spend it in stillness and considering forms of resistance.